别  别  别
No, no, no!
炸鸡粉
FRY BATTER
第四季 第六集
S04E06: Cornered
是我
Uh, it-- it's me.
我只想说
I-- I just wanted to say
我一直惦记着你和孩子们
that I was thinking about you and the kids,
还有
and, uh...
我爱你
I love you.
是我
Uh, it-- it's me.
我只想说
I-- I just wanted to say
我一直惦记着你和孩子们
that I was thinking about you and the kids,
还有
and, uh...
早
Morning.
都日落三竿了
Afternoon.
是吗  天呐
Oh. Really? Jesus.
你不该让我睡的
You shouldn't have let me sleep.
你缺觉
You needed it.
斯凯勒  我记不清昨晚发生的事了
Skyler, I don't entirely remember what happened last night.
我是说  如果
I mean, if...
我说了些...
I said something--
你认识这个叫盖尔・伯蒂彻的吗
Did you know this Gale Boetticher person?
斯凯勒  我酒还没醒
Skyler, I can't even focus. I don't--
盖尔・伯蒂彻
Gale Boetticher.
认识他吗
Did you know him?
天呐  这是怎么了
Oh, my God. What?
我昨晚到底说了什么
What exactly did I say last night?
该说的都说了
Just enough.
你们在一起工作么
Did you work together?
谁杀了他
Who killed him?
是你的老板吗
Was it the people you work for?
当然不是
Definitely not.
这人是不是
Was it somebody who--
也有可能
at some point...
对你下杀手
might want to do the same to you?
应该不会
I seriously doubt it.
不
No.
天呐
God.
Oh, God.
我知道昨晚发生了什么事  沃尔特
I think I know what happened last night, Walt.
我清楚知道昨晚发生的事
Mm. I know exactly what happened last night.
我喝高了
I drank too much wine.
你告诉汉克
You told Hank
他找的人可能还逍遥法外
that the man he was looking for might still be out there,
还说可能根本不是
that it might not be this--
这个叫伯蒂彻的人
...Boetticher after all.
然后我整晚没睡
And I was up all night
一直在想你为什么对他说这些话
wondering why you would say that to him.
因为我喝醉了  斯凯勒
Because I was drunk, Skyler.
不是  可然后
No, but then--
可然后我想起来
but then I was remembering
你的眼睛被打青了
your black eye--
你总不愿提起
your, uh, business disagreement
的工作上的分歧
that you don't want to talk about.
我从不愿谈起这些
I don't want to talk about any of this ever.
防火墙  屏蔽了  不谈了
The firewall, all right?
政教分离  家庭和工作也是
Church and state.
这件事我们就这么处置
That's how we need to approach this thing.
然后我又想起那天你
And then I remembered the message
给我留的言
You left me the other day...
你说你爱我
when you said you loved me.
我听到这句的时候  以为你可能...
When I heard that, I thought that maybe...
你...  我也说不清
you-- I don't know--
我感觉你在忏悔我们之前发生的事
that you were regretting what's happened between us,
我能体会到
and I get that.
但就在昨晚过后
After last night, I--
沃尔特  我觉得你很害怕
Walt, I think you're scared.
我觉得那条留言就像
I think that message was some...
是种道别
kind of goodbye.
斯凯特
Oh, Skyler.
我觉得昨晚你在求救
I think last night was a cry for help.
天呐
Oh, Jesus.
求救
Cry for help.
我认为你心底想让汉克抓住你
I think some part of you wants Hank to catch you.
那真是
That is just--
真是
That is--
就是这样
That is it.
一点没错
Exactly, yes.
你就像是高明的心理医生
You're like Dr. Joyce Brothers here.
天呐
God!
如果他抓住你  至少这些就都结束了
If he caught you, at least this would all be over.
没错  真是个千斤大鼎
Oh, yeah. That's a tremendous weight
重重压在我身上
just lifted off of me.
现在我有了自我认识
Now I-- I understand myself.
多谢  多谢
Thank you. Thank you.
沃尔特
Walt.
我说过
I've said it before.
你要是有危险  就得去报警
If you are in danger, we go to the police.
不  我我想听到警察这字眼
Oh, no. I don't want to hear about the police.
我不是随便说说
I do not say that lightly.
我知道这对我们家可能造成的后果
I know what it could do to this family.
可如果这是我们仅剩的办法
But if it's the only real choice we have--
如果不这么做
if it's either that-- Oh...
你就只能坐以待毙
or your getting shot when you open your front door--
我不想听到警察这字眼
I don't want to hear about the police.
沃尔特  你又不是什么惯犯
You're not some hardened criminal, Walt.
你是无心之过
You're in over your head.
我们就是这么告诉他们的  那是事实
That's what we tell them. That's the truth.
不是事实
That is not the truth.
当然是
Of course it is.
一个中学教师  癌症患者  会急于筹钱
A schoolteacher, cancer, desperate for money?
好了  不说了
Okay, we're done here.
误入歧途而至于身不由己
Roped into working for--
不能收手
Unable to even quit?
沃尔特  那是你亲口说的
You told me that yourself, Walt.
我到底是怎么想的
Jesus, what was I thinking?
沃尔特  求你了
Walt, please.
我们俩
Let's both of us
都别为这整件事争个不停了
stop trying to justify this whole thing
只要承认你有危险就好
and admit you're in danger.
你在跟谁说话呢
Who are you talking to right now?
你面前站着的是什么人  你知道吗
Who is it you think you see?
你知道我一年赚多少吗
Do you know how much I make a year?
即使我告诉你  你也不会相信
I mean, even if I told you, you wouldn't believe it.
你知道我突然半途而废
Do you know what would happen
会有什么下场吗
if I suddenly decided to stop going in to work?
一桩足以登上
A business big enough
纳斯达克席位的大买卖
that it could be listed on the NASDAQ
会破产  瞬间消失
goes belly-up, disappears.
没有我这生意就黄了   不行
It ceases to exist without me. No.
你显然不知道你在跟谁说话
You clearly don't know who you're talking to,
所以我来给你点提示吧
so let me clue you in.
我没有危险  斯凯勒
I am not in danger, Skyler.
我就是个危险人物
I am the danger.
坐以待毙
A guy opens his door and gets shot,
你这么小看我吗
and you think that of me?
不
No.
我是给别人吃枪子的人
I am the one who knocks.
听着  我...
Look, I was--
斯凯勒
Skyler?
看吧
Here we are.
和你离职时一模一样
Just like you left it.
你的漂亮老婆呢
And where is your pretty wife?
她还有其它生意要照看
She has other business to attend to.
照我之前和她说的
Well, like I say to her,
不增不减  明白吗
place is as is. Understand?
是  我明白
Yes, I understand.
好  好
Good. Good.
我可不想她回来又要加条件
I don't want her coming back with more demands.
她砍价的时候可没让我好过
She-- She gave me hard time when we settled on price.
博格丹  我们达成一致了
We're all on the same page, Bogdan.
你要的全在这里
So here's everything you need.
我这儿手续齐全
I keep very good files.
谢谢
Thank you.
你现在是老板了
So you are the boss now, huh?
你准备好了吗
You think you're ready?
我想是吧
Yes, I-- I think so.
当老板要强硬
Being boss is tough.
我知道你觉得我之前在为难你们
I know you think I was hard on you,
但你以后会理解的
but you'll learn.
当家不易
Being in charge is not easy.
需要吃苦耐劳
It takes hard work.
你已经见过我工作卖力了  博格丹
You've seen me work hard, Bogdan.
是吗  我不确定
Yeah? I don't know.
也许还没尽全力吧
Now so much, maybe.
不过也许  你当上老板
But maybe, when you are the boss,
也只会不管不顾
uh, you will just keep your feet up
悠闲自在吧
and relax.
当老板的关键
The real important thing,
这点并不是所有人都知道的
and not everyone knows this is,
就是要强硬
is to be tough.
一个老板必须强硬
A boss has to be tough.
必须对人说不
Has to say no to people.
即使收银员不愿意
Has to make cashiers
也要逼他们
wipe down cars,
出去擦车
even if they don't want to.
你够强硬吗  沃特
Can you be tough, Walter?
我相信你应付得来
I-- I'm sure you can handle.
如果不行
And if not,
你还可以打给你老婆
you can always call your wife, huh?
总是很难打开  没大碍的
Always sticky. No problem.
保持原样
As is.
谁会想到
Who'd have thought
有天我会把这些钥匙交付给你
that someday I would be handing these keys to you?
太多年了  差点忘了
Many years. Almost forgot.
博格丹
Bogdan.
保持原样
As is.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没事吧
You okay there?
很好
Fine.
天黑了  我毒瘾犯了
It's night. I'm not using.
吃点东西吧
Eat something.
喂
Yeah.
没错  他们俩人
That's right. Both of them.
我这就出发
I'm on my way.
需要帮忙吗
You need any help?
不用
No.
想让我打电话  让她回来吗
You want me to call her back?
不用
No. No.
她到底说了什么
But what exactly did she say?
原话
Uh, exactly.
就是
Just, you know,
她问我好不好  让我别担心
she asked if I was okay and not to worry.
之类的
Like that.
说没说她接下来的打算
Any, uh, rough timetable on this thing,
或者提到什么时候回家
or as to when she's coming home?
是因为赌博  对吗
Uh, it's-- it's about the gambling, right?
这有点难
Well, it's-- it's kind of hard to--
她无法理解
She-- She can't understand.
你又不是故意的
It-- it-- It's not like you're doing this on purpose.
可你无法收手
You can't help it.
没这么简单
It's no that simple.
这是一种疾病
Look, you have a disease.
就像嗜酒一样  对吗
It-- It's like you're an alcoholic, right?
不  完全不是
No, it's not. Not at all.
是这样的  我在网上看到的
Yes, it is. I read online.
她甚至不能对你生气
She's not even allowed to be mad at you,
她不能对你的癌症生气  对吗
and she can't be mad at you about the cancer, can she?
不  儿子  这全然不是一回事
No, son, these are two very different things.
不尽然  赌博上瘾就是生病了
Not really. Gambling addiction is a sickness.
-你可以  -听着
- You can... - Listen.
我身上发生的事  与疾病无关
What is going on with me is not about some disease.
只关乎选择
It's about choices--
我既已做出的选择
choices that I have made,
我坚持履行的选择
choices I stand by.
你不会搬回来住了  对吗
You're not moving back in, are you?
不会了
No.
对了
Hey.
这样如何
You know what?
上学一会儿再说
School can wait.
我们绕道去个地方如何
Why don't we take a little detour?
去哪
What kind of detour?
你一去便知
You'll see.
我想是时候给你买辆车了
I think it's time we got you your own car.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
什么
What?
我在想如果你要收买我
I-- I think if you're going to buy me off...
彻底点
buy me off.
太棒了  太棒了
It's amazing. It's amazing.
它长得太帅了
Ah, it's good-looking.
我很高兴你喜欢
I'm glad you like it.
我喜欢  谢谢你  老爸
I-- I do, Thank you, Dad.
好了  不客气
All right. You're welcome.
你来了
So you're here.
是啊
Yeah.
你真的来了  来工作
You're actually here? To work?
是啊  伙计
Yeah, man.
老天
Jesus.
杰西
Jesse.
过来
Come here.
我需要最新消息
All right, I need an update.
什么最新消息
Upda on what?
你和麦克这些外出工作
An update on these little field trips
到底是怎么回事
that you've been taking with Mike.
我已经跟你说了  我们去收钱
I told you already. We pick up money,
检查业务  之类的事
check on things, stuff like that.
你还是他的保镖  对吗
And you're his bodyguard, right?
可是什么  这是你之前说的
But what? That's what you said.
我说我保护了他  就像是支援
I said I guarded him, like backup,
就像是第二双眼
like a second set of eyes.
每个人都需要支援  对吧
Everybody needs backup, right?
那就必须是你么
And this has to be you.
不能是别的...  什么
It can't be... I don't know.
泰鲁斯  或者别的什么古斯雇佣的
Tyrus or any of those couple dozen muscle heads
肌肉猛男
that Gus has working for him?
必须得是杰西・平克曼
It has to be Jesse Pinkman.
为什么
Why?
你有什么我不知道的过人之处
What is there, something about you that I don't know?
你是前海豹部队成员吗
Are you a former Navy SEAL?
你要把你的手
Do you have to have your hands
注册为致命武器吗
registered as lethal weapons?
给你根中指注册吧
Register this.
我要说的是  你都不觉得其中有诈吗
All I'm saying is that do you not even question this?
你真的相信他们需要你吗
Do you really believe that you mean anything to these people?
我不是要出口伤人
And I'm not trying to be insulting.
我只是想让你想清楚
I'm just trying to make you see things clearly.
我看他们不是要杀我
I see they can't outright kill me,
他们是不想看我吸毒
but they don't want me getting high.
我是从古斯让麦克看着我的时候起
I see this thing probably started
就这么感觉了
as Gus getting Mike to babysit me.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
我保护了麦克不被抢劫
I saved Mike from getting robbed,
他甚至可能被杀
even killed, maybe.
所以我可能压根就不是个窝囊废
So maybe I'm not such a loser after all.
那如果...
I mean, what if it--
老天
Oh, God.
如果这一切只是圈套呢
I mean, what if-- what if it's all just a setup?
-什么  -如果你阻止的那次抢劫
- What? - What if this robbery that you stopped
不是真的呢
wasn't even real?
好好想想
I mean, think about it.
你给麦克放风的头一天
Your first day out guarding Mike.
他一出车门  就有情况发生
he steps out for one second, and what happens?
你立刻就被抢劫
You immediately get robbed.
你简直混蛋
You are such an asshole.
接近朋友  更要接近敌人
Keep your friends close, keep your enemies closer.
就像你说的
Like you said,
因为有我  古斯不可能杀你
Gus can't kill you because of me.
他知道我不会坐视不管的
He knows I won't stand for it.
他需要我  又不想接受他需要我这个事实
He needs me, and he hates the fact that he needs me,
那他该怎么办呢  他就试图
so what does he do? He goes to work
离间我和你的关系
driving a wedge between you and me.
你真是个混球  你要是在场
You're an asshole. If you'd been there,
你就知道那不是圈套
you'd know it wasn't a setup.
等一下  这些家伙追你多长时间了
Wait a minute. How long did those guys chase you?
就你的描述来看
Huh? Because the way you describe it,
他们也太容易就放弃了
they gave up pretty damn easy.
不  不  这
No, no. This--
这整件事  所有的一切
This whole thing, all of this--
都是因为我
it's all about me.
喂
Hello.
你是谁  等下
Uh, who is it? Hang on.
是我
Yeah.
我马上上去
I'll be right up.
怎么了
What?
我得走了
I got to go.
那我要自己把这都打扫干净么
Well, am I supposed to clean all this on my own?
天呐
God.
(西班牙语:)  早上好
(Spanish:)  Buenos días,
女士们
ladies.
早上好
Buenos días.
你们会说英语么
Uh, do you speak English?
-你会说英语么
-?Se habla inglés?
-不会  不会
- No. No.
不会  好吧
No. Okay, uh...
帮忙怎么说  帮忙怎么说
help, help--
帮...帮芒
Uh, ayon-- ayonda--
-帮忙  -帮忙  没错  谢谢  谢谢
- Ayuda.  - Ayuda, ayuda. Gracias, gracias.
你需要  哦不  应该是我需要清洁上的帮忙
Uh, yo necesita-- necesito ayuda a limpio.
好么 好么
?Sí? ?Sí?
- 什么?    - 我需要人帮我做清扫
- ?Qué?    - I need help to clean.
是的  好么  明白了么
Yes, sí, ?comprendes, sí?
不 不  不  很好
No, no, no. Es bueno.
请  请
Uh... Uh, por favor, por favor.
后边来  后边来 好么
Atrás, atrás, ?sí?
非常好  非常好
Muy bueno, muy bueno.
对  非常好
Yes, muy bueno.
-就是这个  -不行
- It's just this-- - No.
不  不  不  不  我们不能
No, no, no, no. No podemos.
我们不能
No podemos.
抱歉
Lo siento.
别  别  别  这没问题
No, no, no, no. Es no problema.
等一下  等一下  等一下
Un momento, un momento, un momento.
这没问题的
No problema.
别  别  女士们
No, no, ladies.
等一下  等一下
Un momento, un momento.
帮我个忙
Yo necesito ayuda, uh...
最多两个小时
limpio dos horas máximo.
-不  我们不能这样做  -很简单的工作
- No, no podemos. - Muy fácil.
让我看看  让我看看  等一下
Let me see. Let me see. Un momento.
这么着  这么着
I'll tell you what. I'll tell you what.
看  看  看
Look, look, look.
世界通用语  钱
Universal language. Dinero.
给你
?Para usted?
好么  好么
Sí? sí? sí?
给你  好么  给你
Para usted, sí? Para usted.
还有一张给你  好么
There's one for you. Yes, sí?
格兰特总统  非常重要的人物
Presidente Grant. Very important man.
好么  给你  好么
sí? Para usted, sí? sí?
更多的钱
And más dinero--
完事有更多的钱
más dinero after--
可以了么
Are we good?
我觉得可以了
I think we're good.
我觉得我们听你的就行
I think we listened to you.
来吧  请  请
Please. Por favor. Por favor.
快点
Vamos.
最多两个小时  好么
Dos horas máximo, ?sí?
来吧  请  请
Please. Por favor. Por favor.
太好了
Yes.
一起来吧
Iguales!
什么活
What's the deal?
我们的活就是看着那栋房子
Uh, the deal is we're watching that house.
前面左边门前有棵树的那栋
A couple down on the left with the tree in the front.
是么  为什么
Yeah? What for?
有只小鸟告诉我  那里面有一些家伙
A little birdie told me there's some guys in there
拿着我们三磅的货
that have 3 pounds of our product
想出手
which they're selling
而且那些货不是从我们手里买的
and which they sure as hell didn't get from us.
那计划是什么
So what's the plan?
我刚告诉你了
I just told you.
我们坐在这看着那栋房子
We sit here and watch that house
直到里面其中一个"企业家"露出头来
until one of our entrepreneurs pops his head out.
然后我们问几个问题  把东西拿回来
Then we ask a few questions and get our property back.
我们为什么不直接破门而入
Why don't you just go break the door down
用手枪告诉那些混蛋谁才是老大
and pistol whip those bitches and show them who's boss?
因为这只小鸟还告诉我
Because a little birdie also told me
这些家伙对这些产品很上瘾
these guys are heavily into the product
还喜欢带枪
and most likely armed.
现在  对于瘾君子你所不知道的是
Now, what you may not know about meth heads--
也许你知道的
maybe you do--
他们都有点不按套路出牌
they're kind of unpredictable.
我不喜欢不按套路出牌的人
I don't care for unpredictable,
所以我们等着
so we wait.
抱歉打破你的幻想  孩子
Sorry to burst your bubble, kid,
但这就是这个工作的大部分内容
but that's 90% of the job.
别担心
Don't worry.
我带了三明治
I brought sandwiches.
是的先生
Yes, sir.
辣椒芝士  听上去诱人吧
pimiento cheese. How does that sound?
你要去哪
Where are you going?
他们不是在卖么
So they're selling, right?
我想买点
Maybe I'm looking to buy.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
塔克
Tucker!
我想买点货
I'm, uh, here to buy.
-答非所问
-Not my question.
-塔克  你能关上那倒霉门么  塔克
-Tucker! Will you shut the damn door? Tucker!
我的名字叫迪塞尔
Uh, my name's Diesel.
据说你们这有那些蓝色的货
Thought you maybe had some of the blue?
塔克  关门  塔克
Tucker! Shut the door, Tucker!
- 我只是  - 塔克
- I'm just, uh--  - Tucker!
想要爽一下
...just looking for a teenth.
-塔克  -给点力
- Tucker!  - Yo. Come on.
-塔克  -帮兄弟一把
- Tucker!  - Help a brother out.
塔克  你能把门关上么
Tucker, will you shut the damn door?
我们不和陌生人做交易
We don't sell to strangers.
塔克
Tucker!
滚吧  混蛋
Get off the porch, asshole.
塔克  你能把门关上么
Tucker, will you shut the door?
好了  已经关了  老天
All right already! Jesus!
塔克
Tucker!
我猜我们还得执行第一套方案了
Guess we'll go with Plan A, then.
打开后备箱
Flip the trunk, will you?
为什么
Why?
那里面有我需要的东西
There's something in there I need.
什么东西
And what would that be?
我要把那群杂种从房子里赶出来
I'm getting those pricks out of that house.
你第一次尝试就够成功的了
Oh, your first attempt being such a wild success.
也许你是蹲点狙击的专家
You may know this whole P.I. Sit-in-the-car business,
但我更懂瘾君子的思想
but I know meth heads.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
挖坑
Digging.
为什么
Why?
你知道为什么
Uh, you know why.
挖多深
How deep are you going?
不知道
I don't know.
你觉得有多深
How deep do you think it is?
很深
Pretty deep.
你能来接力一下么
you mind taking over for a minute?
好的  当然
Yeah. Sure.
我能用用你的厕所么
Hey, uh, mind if I use your john?
当然
Yeah.
塔克
Tucker!
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是
I-- Hey.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
我
Hey, I'm, uh--
我是塔克的朋友
I'm a friend of Tucker's.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我只是
I just, uh--
只是想  想买点蓝色的货
just want to-- just want to buy some of the blue.
不卖
It's not for sale.
我知道之前你一直在卖
Well, I know you were selling it earlier, so--
是吗  你怎么知道的
Yeah? How do you know that?
塔克告诉我的
Uh, Tucker told me.
他妈的他倒是该学学
Yeah, well, Tucker needs to learn
怎么管住自己那张嘴了
to keep his dame mouth shut.
塔克
Tucker!
Tucker?
所以
So, uh...
能卖给我点吗
you going to help me out?
没那么多可以卖给塔克那帮混蛋朋友
Don't have enough for all of Tucker's asshole friends.
塔克
Tucker!
他在外面呢
Yo, I-- I think he's outside.
你能不能
Why don't you just--
你能不能去外面找他
why don't you go outside--
塔克  塔克
Tucker! Tucker!
我们去找他吧
Hey, hey. Let's go-- Let's go find Tucker.
去外面找他
Okay? Let's go outside and--
我没有多余的货卖给你  明白吗
I don't have enough for you, all right?
明白  明白
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
我不要了  行了吧
Forget it. Okay?
我可不想惹麻烦
I don't want to-- i don't want to start any trouble.
麻烦  什么麻烦
Trouble? Trouble?
你什么意思
What does that mean, trouble?
不  不  我是说咱俩没事了
No, no. I'm just saying we're cool, okay?
没事了
We're-- We're-- We're good.
什么  你怎么知道
What? You can't know that.
你到底什么意思
What does that mean?
别骗我
What-- Don't put thoughts in my head!
你别想骗我
You don't put thoughts in my head!
是  是  你说的对
Absolutely. You're right.
你说的对
You're right.
塔克
Tucker.
谢谢  十分感谢
muchas, muchas gracias, amigas.
非常感谢  给你
Muchas gracias. Here you go.
谢谢
Oh, gracias.
玛莉亚  维尼塔  露西亚  谢谢
María, Vernita, Lucía, gracias.
非常感谢
Muchas gracias.
这句没听懂  不过应该是好话
I missed that one. I'm sure it was good.
女士们  跟我来
Damas. Vengan conmigo.
告诉我  你要带她们去哪
Tell me... Where are you taking them?
泰鲁斯  你要干嘛
Come on, Tyrus, what are you doing?
我要送她们上车
I'm putting them on a bus.
什么车  为什么
Why? What bus?
送她们回洪都拉斯的车
One that takes them back to Honduras.
等等  等一下
Hey, wait a second. Wait a minute.
这都是我的主意
Th-Th-This was my idea.
别惩罚她们
Don't punish them.
你让古斯冲着我来
You tell Gus to blame me, not them.
就是冲着你来的
He does.
你回避一下行吗
Give us a minute, will you?
不会太久的
We won't be too long.
劫车的那伙人把我们的货
The crew that hit our truck gave away the cargo
送给附近的无名小卒
to a couple of local nobodies.
很有纪律
Very disciplined, though,
自己一点都没留
not keeping anything for themselves.
他们这么做
It was all about sending a message,
只为传递一个信息
which they did, literally.
都写在桶盖上了
It was written on the bucket lid.
准备好谈谈了吗
"Ready to talk?"
翻译过来应该是这个意思
That, I believe, is the English translation.
你也许不想听我的意见
I know you're not really asking for advice,
但如果给我
but let me hire 10, 15
10到15能干的人
more good operators,
我就能狠狠的教训他们一下
and we hit them back, hit them hard,
把他们赶回老家去
hit them where they live.
不
No.
暂时不要开战
This war stays cold for now.
那他们的消息怎么办  你准备怎么应对
What about their message? What's the answer?
安排他们和我见面
Set up a meeting.
看看他们想要说什么
Let's see what they have to say.
他今天表现怎么样
How did he do today?
听说你干得不错
I hear you can handle yourself.
可能吧
I guess.
晚安
Good night.
等等
Uh, excuse me.
为什么找我
Why me?
我相信我看人的眼光
I like to think I see things in people.
慢点吃  车又不会自己跑掉
Slow down. The car is not going anywhere.
妈
Mom.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetheart.
宝宝你去那
Whoo. Ah. There you go.
你看见外面那辆车了吗
Did you see what's in the driveway?
看见了
Uh, yeah, I saw.
你的吗
So that's yours, huh?
是啊  爸给我买的
Yeah. Dad got it for me.
他真好啊
That was very nice of him.
是啊
Yeah.
我知道那车看起来很炫
I-- I know it looks like...
但很安全的
well, awesome, but it's super safe.
爸他检查过了
Dad-- Dad made sure.
我保证绝不超速
And I promise to always go the speed limit
一定慢慢开
or below, way below.
而且这车超省油的
And it gets great gas mileage.
爸说我可以开出去兜兜风
So Dad said I can take it around the block a few times.
可以吗
That okay?
就在附近转转
Just around the block.
好吧  别开太远
Yeah. Just around the block.
还有小心点  行吗
And be careful, okay?
好的
I will.
拜
Bye.
妈
I-It-- It's really--
有你在家真好
It's really great to have you home, Mom.
一定要小心  听见了吗
Hey, seriously, be careful, okay?
知道了
I will.
好
Okay.
我们谈谈吧
I guess we should talk.
那天谈得够多了
Oh, I think you said plenty the other day.
关于那个  我只是
No. Look, about that, it just--
你拿到洗车房的钥匙了吗
Did you get the car wash keys?
拿到了
Um, yes, yes.
斯凯勒  我那天说的
Skyler, I may have...
可能有点夸张了
overstated things earlier,
我为我的失言感到抱歉
and I'm sorry to be so forward.
但是  我只想
But I-- I just--
让你知道
I want you to know something.
我想让你
I want you to--
想让你明白
I need you to understand
你是安全的
that you are safe.
你  儿子还有女儿
You, Junior, Holly--
你们都是安全的
you are completely safe.
我所做的一切
Everything that I do-- everything--
都是为了保护这个家庭
I do it to protect this family.
所以  你买车
So buying that car,
也是在保护这个家吗
that was protecting your family?
好吧
Okay. I, uh--
我承认这件事做的有点鲁莽
All right, maybe it's a little flashy,
但他想要辆车
but he needed a car, and--
我是他父亲
and I'm his father,
理应完成他的愿望不是吗
and I should be able to get what he wants.
明天把车退回去
It goes back tomorrow.
斯凯勒  他会伤心死的
Skyler, it will crush him.
买车会戳破我们的谎
That car directly contradicts our story.
如果你真的在意  想保护这个家庭
And if you're so invested in protecting this family,
你就要圆这个谎
it means protecting the story.
你觉得邻居会怎么想  沃尔特
What do you think the neighbors are going to say, Walt?
汉克和玛丽呢
What about Hank and Marie?
还有国税局
How about the IRS?
你到底在想什么  沃尔特
What were you thinking, Walt?
我想的是
I was thinking
我想为我儿子做点什么
that I wanted to do something nice for my son.
听着
Look.
我担心他会因此怨恨你
I just worry that he'll blame you for this.
他当然会
Oh, he will.
多亏了你  他要再一次地怨恨他的贱人妈妈
Once again, he'll blame his bitch mother
怨她拿走了他敬爱的父亲
for taking away what his loving father has given him,
送他的东西
so thanks for that.
但你知道吗  沃尔特
But you know what, Walt?
比起你这个只会嘴上说着保护
Someone has to protect this family
我才是真正在保护这个家的人
from the man who protects this family.